见鬼  抱歉  小妞
Shit. Sorry, girl.
最后一洞
Final hole.
来个小鸟低杆球
He birdies here,
穿着绿色上衣走开
he walks away with the green jacket.
靠
Fuck!
太好了
Wonderful.
你迟到了
You're late.
问问这个狗娘养等下我们有什么大不了的
告诉你老板  我会西班牙语
他再叽叽歪歪  我就干他娘的
- The weapons? - It's on the boat. The cash?
-武器呢  -在船上  钱呢
- Feels a little light. - That's 45,000 now.
-有点轻哦  -先给4万5千美元
武器到手之后
The rest you'll get wired into an account of your choosing
-剩下的钱你给个账号我网上转账给你  -不行  不行  不行
- once we get the weapons. - No, no, no!
这太扯淡了  我们事先可不是这样说的
This is bullshit! This is not what we agreed on!
嘿  帕波罗  马可  皮佩  管你叫啥名字
Hey, Pablo, paco, pepe, whatever the fuck your name is.
别动船上的武器
Leave the weapons on the boat.
好  好说
Okay. Fine.
你想玩我是吧  那我们来好好玩玩
You want to play games? I'll play games.
事先提醒你  我讨厌玩心眼
But I'll have you know, I hate games.
校对  Luckydag
事实上  我小学没毕业的原因
In fact, I quit grade school
就是因为课间休息时玩得太多了
because of motherfucking recess!
时间轴  Loriaef
我们说好了价钱
We agreed on a set price.
我准备好武器  在这儿交货
I get the weapons, I drop them off here.
后期  Loriaef
作为交换  你付我十五万现金
You pay me 150,000 cash for my troubles.
-十五万现金  -四万五千
- 150,000 cash. - 45,000 cash.
QQ  2196656020
见鬼  对不起
Oh, shit. I'm sorry.
蒙蒂  真没料到这个情况  要不这样吧
I didn't realize this is let's make a deal. Okay, monty.
四万五千美元  我只能给你等价的武器
Forty-give grand for $45,000 worth of weapons.
嘿  得了  得了  等等  等等
Hey, hey, come on. Come on. Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
等等
Wait!
瑞恩  去拿包  去拿武器
Ryan, get the bags, get the weapons.
这可不好  老兄
Not cool, hombre.
这事我习惯了  兄弟
I can do this all day, amigo.
靠
Fuck!
-啊  我靠  -空包弹
- Oh, shit. - Blanks.
罗根  罗根  罗根
Logan. Logan. Logan.
罗根
Logan!
罗根  罗根
Logan. Logan!
罗根
Logan!
这就是现今社会的悲伤写照
Well, this is a sad commentary on today's society.
杰克  别往心里去
Don't take it too personal, Jack.
别骗自己了  搭档  怎么能不在意呢
Don't kid yourself, partner. It's always personal.
顺便问下  我干掉最后两个家伙的时候
Ps, where the fuck were you
你死那里去了
on those last two?
老大  基本射击要领  枪目线过于模糊
Marksmanship 101, boss. Gun-target line was shit.
我射击用的是点308麦格伦弹
I'm firing .308 win mags.
啊  对了  你头发里沾了点脑浆
Oh, by the way, you got some brain in your hair.
-老天  -这个距离  一颗点308弹
- Jesus Christ! - At this range, a .308 woulda ripped right through
会直穿过你刚杀的"生意伙伴"
your recently deceased business partners
在你胸口爆个大洞
and left you with a sucking chest wound.
幸好你没干  好了  大伙儿撤吧
Well, good to know. All right, let's get the hell out of here.
马上过来  老板大人
On my way, boss man.
那个帅小伙的弹夹有真子弹是怎么回事
What happened with Gabriel's rounds?
我拿不到他的备用弹夹
I couldn't get to his spare mags.
-他会注意到的  -会害死人的
- He would have noticed! - That could have been bad.
-差点而已  -
- Could have. -
顺便说下  你这两个家伙都是蠢材
You guys are fucking idiots, by the way.
空包弹这种计策玩多了会出事的
How many more times you think you're going to get away with this blanks shit?
你的语气听来好像很关心这事
Is that concern I hear in your voice?
当然  这可关系到我的前途啊
Yeah, concern for my future employment.
我的综合技能在星巴克可找不到相应的职位
My skill set doesn't exactly translate to working at Starbucks.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
够走运的话
I'll see you in a couple of weeks.
过几个星期会再见面
If you're lucky.
得了  出点力嘛  一起来
Come on, let's see what you got. Come on. There you go.
嘿  嘿  嘿  别这么大力推我
Hey, hey, hey. Don't push me too hard.
珍 宝 大 战
艾迪  爱德华的简称
能给我拿条毛巾吗
Can you grab me a towel?
这是什么
What the fuck is this?
-你指什么  -这照片
- What the fuck is what? - This!
-你那儿找到的  -简娜会气疯的
- Where'd you find that? - Jenna would be pissed.
-简娜和我仅仅  简娜和我  我只是说
- Jenna and me have only-- - Jenna and I. I'm just saying.
简娜和我才约会了几个星期
Jenna and I have only been dating for a few weeks.
-我要把这照片扔了  -
- I'm throwing this out. -
好  我不在乎  扔掉它吧
Fine. I don't care. Throw it out.
哇  印象深刻啊
Wow. I'm impressed.
说说看  距最后一次听到她的消息  过多久了
When's the last time you heard from her, anyway?
不好说
I don't know.
六个月吧
Six months.
杰克  知道么  你可真是个没骨气的奇葩
You're a real nutless wonder, you know that, Jack?
实话说  你究竟见过她没有
Honestly. What the hell did you ever see in her?
所有人趴下
Everybody down!
听到没  快行动
Get that. Let's go!
-爱德华  你好  -很高兴你终于接了电话
- Hello, Edward. - So glad you picked up.
我正忙着呢
I'm kind of in the middle of something right now,
要不回头打给你吧
so I'll probably just call you back.
我知道你在那儿  也清楚你正在干什么
I know where you are and I know what you are doing.
难道你忘了
Or did you forget who planned
这一切最早出是谁的计划吗
this little trip in the first place?
艾迪  是你叫停它的
You called this job off, Eddie.
艾迪  是你叫停这个计划的
所以你不能责怪我提前行事
So you can't blame me for going ahead with this.
我还是得责怪你
But I do blame you.
你正在执行我酝酿成熟的计划
You're doing a job that I planned.
这计划是我从头到尾设计好的
A job that I set up.
你可要付我"中介费"哦
There are finder's fees associated with it.
你的计划自己叫停  我决定继续执行而已
Your job you called off and I decided to move forward with?
凯伦  没我的首肯  没我的参与
Without me. Without my permission, Karen.
爱德华  你要什么
What do you want, Eddie?
-我全部的分成  -那是多少
- My full share. - Which is?
-100%分成  -不是说好60%吗
- One hundred percent. - What happened to 60?
另外40%算是你对我侮辱的补偿
Well, the additional 40 is for the indignity that I have suffered.
-没门
- No fucking way.
凯伦  别这么说
Yes fucking way, Karen.
你报了警吗
You called the cops?
我还能说什么  你做的事真伤感情
What can I say? My feelings were hurt.
-你将什么都得不到  -
- You'll get nothing. -
早就想给你个难忘的教训
A price I would gladly pay
这个代价我认为值得
to teach you a long overdue lesson.
现在  格伦
Now, Glenn,
跟我说说为什么你的领带像沾过屎一样
why is it that these ties look like they were dipped in shit?
-你是说屎吗  费罗萨先生  -屎
- Shit, Mr. filosa? - Shit. Yes.
先生  你要求的深红色树状条纹
Sir, you asked for Scarlet forest,
我确信这些领带的颜色正是你要的
and I assure you these ties are all Scarlet forest.
-你跟我保证这颜色是对的吗  -是的  先生
- You're assuring me that? - Yes, sir.
我跟你说这些领带像沾过屎一样
I'm assuring you that they look like they were dipped in shit.
看看这个
See this?
看看这个颜色
See this color?
等它干了  才会是我想要的领带颜色
When that dries, that's the color I want on these ties.
-是的  先生  -你可以走了
- Yes, sir. - Off you go.
假如凯伦能活着出来
If Karen makes it out alive,
她将不得不搭乘原来那班飞机
she'll have no choice but to take her original flight.
把她知道的一切都给我挖出来
I need to know exactly what she knows.
明白  先生
Yes, sir.
只剩几天功夫了
It's only a matter of days now.
这个计划  我的计划就在那里
This job, my job is right out there.
可不能让凯伦给搞砸了
We can't let Karen fuck it up.
-绝对不行  -为什么
- Absolutely fucking not. - Why not?
原因嘛  你借我狗狗
Why? 'Cause the fact that you borrow my dog
只不过想讨你那兽医女友的欢心罢了
in order to trick your veterinarian girlfriend
一想到你是个动物爱好者就觉得可悲
to thinking you're an animal lover is pathetic.
我一向是动物爱好者  只不过没养过宠物而已
I am an animal lover, I'm just not an animal owner.
-你真的喜欢这个女人么  -
- Do you even like this woman? -
当然  我喜欢她  非常喜欢
Yes, I like this woman. I like her a lot.
那为什么一直对她撒谎
Then why do you continue to lie to her?
我撒谎是因为我爱她
I lie to her because I like her!
哈  哼  你说话像个需要慰藉的男人
Ha. Well, spoken like a true man.
别说了
Stop it.
明天上午把狗还给我
I want her home by morning.
前台  是的  他在这儿  好  我转告他
Reception. Yeah, he's right here. All right, I'll let him know.
她准备好见你了
She's ready for you.
康纳医生跟海狮一起待在后面
Dr. Connor's in the back with a sea lion, okay?
-起来  我们走  -
- Let's go. Come on. -
啊  对了  她最喜欢雏菊
Oh. And daisies are her favorites.
-你懂的  下次带上  -多谢相告
- You know, for next time. - Now you tell me.
-干得好
- Good job.
过来
Come on.
凯利  它今天好多了
She's doing much better today, Kerry.
医生  我这里有个病狗狗
I have another patient for you, Doc.
嗨  格雷丝
Hi, Grace! Hi!
-我想它记得你  -应该是
- I think she remembers you. - I think so.
-这些花是给我的吗  -对
- Are those for me? - Yes.
-爱煞玫瑰了  -噢
- I love roses. - Yeah.
-协商的事怎么样  -我干掉了他们
- How was the conference? - I knocked them dead.
当然  我就知道
Of course. I knew you would.
-今晚共进晚餐好吗  -唔...两个条件
- How about dinner tonight? - Hmm... two conditions.
-尽管说  -你下厨
- Name them. - You cook.
-好说  -格雷丝得在场
- Done. - And Grace is there.
当然  格雷丝总赖在那儿
Of course. Grace will always be there.
-嗨  宝贝  -格雷丝  她是谁呀
- Hi, baby. Hi! - Who's that, Grace?
刚有手下给我电话  她已经到了机场
One of my men just called. They spotted her arriving at the airport.
-他们正跟踪着她  -她一个人做不来
- They're following her now. - She can't do it alone.
-找出她的帮手  -好的  先生
- Find them. - Yes, sir.
格雷丝  格雷丝  闭嘴
Grace! Grace, shut up!
杰克...
Mm, Jack...
-天啦  我靠
- Jesus! Fuck!
嗨
Hi.
你来这儿干什么
What the fuck are you doing here?
杰克  很高兴见到你
Good to see you too, Jack.
你怀孕了
Are you pregnant?
你家的剩菜看起来好美味  我去吃点
I'm going to go eat your leftovers 'cause they look delicious.
你俩接着办事
And I'll let you two finish up here.
我得说一句  记得戴套套哦
Use a condom. That's all I'm going to say.
杰克  那女人是谁
Jack, who is that woman?
-喂  -我找到他们了  先生
- Yeah. - I found them, sir.
-好  -他们活不过明天早晨
- Good. - They'll be dead by morning.
-事情办好  -是  先生
- Finish it. - Yes, sir.
-几个月了  -有番茄酱吗
- How many months? - Got any pickles?
-凯伦... -是你的孩子
- Karen... - It's yours.
我明白  刚开始那会儿我也拒绝接受事实
I know. I was in denial too for a little while.
哀伤的五个阶段嘛  那是第一个阶段
It's the first of five stages of grief.
-那么  有...你TMD上那儿去了
- Then there is-- - where the fuck have you been?!
接着是愤怒
Then there's anger.
-我得走了  -噢  简娜...简娜
- I'm going to go. - Oh! Jenna... Jenna.
简娜  别  真对不起  你知道我
Jenna, please, I'm so sorry about this, you know... I...
格雷丝  别吵
Grace! Please!
-要我回头给你电话吗  -好  那当然
- Do you want to call me later? - Yes, of course.
等我一下  格雷丝  格雷丝  别叫了
Gimme a second. Grace. Grace, knock it off!
对不起  等我一下  我陪你...
I'm sorry. Just give me one second, I'll walk you...
格雷丝  得了  闭嘴
Grace! Come on, girl. Shut up!
噢  见鬼
Oh, shit!
简娜  你得听我的说
Jenna, I need you to listen to me.
马上就有很危险的事情发生
Something very dangerous is about to happen.
别问任何问题  明白吗
You can not ask any questions. Do you understand me?
-什么  -你刚提了个问题
- What? - That was a question!
枪  你有枪
Guns? You have guns?
杰克  那是个手雷吗
Jack, is that a grenade?
什么  杰克
What? Jack!
-你我之间得谈谈  -现在吗
- You and me are going to talk. - Now?
-快去船那儿  -快走
- Get to the boat. - Let's go.
-跑  快跑  快跑
- Move! Move! Move!
快点  简娜  进船里去
Let's go! Come on, Jenna, get in the boat!
快  狗狗  快进来
Come on, girl! Let's go!
-凯伦  趴低  -在码头那儿
- Karen, get down! - The dock!
追  快追  快点追
Move, move, move!
快上船
Get on the boat!
-杰克  -凯伦  你等下
- Jack! - Give me a minute, Karen.
-但我... -你没看到我竖起手指吗
- Yeah, but i-- - did you see the finger?!
-杰克  我看到了  -竖着手指是说
- Yes, Jack, I see the finger! - Well, the finger means
-我需要一分钟思考的时间  -
- I need one minute to think! -
他们追上来了
Here they come!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
-我在打电话报警  -给我手机
- I'm calling the police! - Give me that!
别叫警察
There's no calling the police!
啊
Ah!
-杰克  我们这是去那里  -
- Where are we going, Jack? -
简娜  那里安全去那里
Somewhere safe, Jenna.
-凯伦  好了  开枪  -
- Okay, Karen, go. -
有人认为我偷了他的东西
Someone thinks I stole from him.
-凯伦  你偷了吗  -什么
- Did you? Karen! - What?!
-你偷了人家东西吗  -没
- Did you steal from someone? - No!
上帝保佑  事前你怎么不仔细想想
Jesus Christ! Do you ever think anything through?!
哦  别跟我说做事鲁莽那套屁话
Oh, don't talk to me about thinking things through!
你总是想得多  做得少
You over analyze everything!
我喜欢事前计划
I like to plan!
才不会像你这样落到今天的境地
I like to plan so I don't get into shit like this!
别吵了  把注意力转到那帮追杀者那儿吧
Please just pay attention to the people trying to kill us!
开快点  开快点  追上去
Faster! Faster! Let's go!
-我在爱德华・费罗萨那里接了一个活  -
- I ran a job for Eddie filosa. -
哦  这是第一个错误
Oh, mistake number one.
-你认识他吗  -打过交道
- You know him? - I know of him.
出了岔子  事情没做成
Well, the job went south and we lost the score.
再正常不过
Well, that happens.
哦  你去跟爱德华说吧  他要我赔偿损失
Yeah, well, tell that to Eddie. He wants me to make good for it!
-所有损失吗  -所有损失
- All of it? - All of it!
-多大  -非常大
- How big? - Huge!
-这不合常理  -
- That's not very rational. -
杰克  爱德华喜欢不按常理出牌
Eddie's not exactly rational, Jack.
-她没事吧  -没事
- Is she okay? - She's fine.
-罗根的狗跟着我们做什么  -
- What is Logan's dog even doing here? -
格雷丝是罗根的狗吗
Grace is Logan's dog?
-她还不知道吗  -我正想告诉你
- She didn't know? - I was going to tell you.
杰克  你要讲的是事实的那一部分
You were going to tell me what part, Jack?
是关于格雷丝不是你的狗
That Grace isn't yours,
还是关于你把前女友搞大了肚子
that you got an ex-girlfriend pregnant,
还是你是某种超级大罪犯
or that you're some type of uber-criminal?!
杰克  她说得有道理
She's got a point, Jack.
开快点  追上去
Come on, faster! Go!
你能干掉那个摩托艇吗
Can you take out that jet ski?
这枪没子弹了  当然我能干掉摩托艇
I'm out! Of course I can take out the jet ski!
你这枪有问题
There's something wrong with your gun!
凯伦  我的枪没问题
There's nothing wrong with my gun, Karen.
哦  真的么
Oh, really?
那为什么不让这位"当代女友"试试
Then why don't we let "this year's model" give it a try?
-别太过分  -
- Just leave her alone. -
为什么  我懂了  她喜欢躺在后面避风头
Why? I know she likes to just lay on her back,
也许她应该帮我们分担点压力
but maybe she wants to participate more.
杰克  你怎么看上这种女人的
What the hell did you ever see in this woman, Jack?
我接受他开着灯做爱的习惯  够了吧
I gave him a reason to fuck with the lights on!
-杰克  -什么
- Jack! - What?
摩托艇都干掉了
There are no more jet skis.
坏消息是  枪也没有了
The bad news, no more guns.
-还剩下什么  -霰弹枪
- What do we got left? - A shotgun.
这么远的距离  打不中的
We're never going to hit them from this distance.
-我要让船做平旋运动  -真的吗
- I'm going to flatspin the boat. - Really?
就像在巴西那次
Just like Brazil.
啊
Ah!
凯伦  你来掌方向
Karen! Take the wheel!
-把它弄出去  -快上
- Get her out of here! - Go!
杰克  你要干什么
Jack, what are you doing? Jack!
你他妈的
Fucking bitch!
-我靠  -天啦
- Oh, shit! - Oh, god!
操
Fuck!
格雷丝  过来这里  狗狗  快来
Grace, get over here, girl. Come on!
你还好吧
Are you all right?
-简娜  能跟你谈几句吗  -好
- Jenna, can I talk to you for a minute, please? - Yeah.
我要你找个旅馆住上几天
I need you to get a hotel for the next few days.
请个病假  别告诉同事你去那里
Call in sick to work. Don't tell them where you are.
不想去旅馆  我要回家
I don't want to get a hotel. I want to go home.
我明白你现在有点不知所措
I understand you're a bit overwhelmed right now,
但我过去多次遇到这种情况
but I've been through these things in the past, a few times.
你一定要相信我
You're just going to have to trust me.
-你一起来吗  -
- Are you coming with me? -
现在不行  过阵子我会来看你的
Not right now, but I'll come back to check on you.
你要跟她一起走么
Are you going somewhere with her?
很不巧  我得跟她去
Yeah. Unfortunately.
我得搞清楚究竟发生了什么  找出解决方案
I need to figure out what's going on. I need some answers.
跟你在一起可办不成事
I'm not going to get those with you around.
-你要给她上水刑吗  -不
- Are you going to waterboard her? - No.
我不会给她上水刑的  我只是..
I'm not going to waterboard her, I just...
我只是不想让你再进一步卷入事中
I just don't want you to get more involved than you already are.
我觉得你该给她上水刑
I think you should waterboard her.
好了  关于这一切...我非常抱歉
Okay. I'm sorry... About all this.
-我也是  -罗根明天早晨会来领格雷丝
- Me too. - Logan'll be by in the morning to pick up Grace.
好
Okay.
格雷丝  最惨的部分是  约会太糟糕了
The saddest part, Grace, I've had worse dates.
嘿  你们中有人知道老板在那儿吗
Anyone seen the boss? Hey!
有人知道吗
Anyone seen the boss?
真像...
Like really...
搞什么  你们这帮小娘们
What the fuck? You bitches.
你搞什么  有病啊你  神经
What the fuck? What's your problem, psycho?
你  "****"
You. Dick breath.
嘿  别这样子对我们说话
Hey! You can't talk to us like that.
你不服
Yes, I can.
你们有什么问题
What's the matter with you?
你究竟在这儿干什么  女孩们
What the fuck are you doing, girls?
我来问你个问题  你们怎么理财的
Let me ask you a question. How do you invest your money?
-什么  -理财
- What? - Invest.
艾迪付你们钱的  对不  那些钱你们怎么用
Eddie pays you, right? What do you do with your money?
-用来买东西  -买些什么
- I buy shit. - You buy shit like what?
-鞋子  -鞋子  还有呢
- Shoes. - Shoes. And?
-漂亮的鞋子  -太好了  还有别的吗
- Nice shoes. - Great. What else?
-胸前的大咪咪  -漂亮着呢
- These boobs. - They're nice boobs, by the way.
硬汉  有话直说  没功夫跟你耗一天
What's your point, tough guy? We don't have all day.
我的意思是你们也许有两三年功夫
My point is you got about two, maybe three more years
出卖自己的身体  然后呢
of whoring yourself out before a whole new batch of younger
等着一帮更年青漂亮的小妞
and prettier whores comes rolling in through that front door.
从那扇大门进来取代你们
And all you're going to have to show for it
而你们剩下的不过是满柜的旧鞋子和破败的身体
is a closet full of old shoes, and a banged up pussy.
如果我是女人  像你这般年青  这般好身材
Now, if I had a vagina, and I had your ass,
这般美貌  我肯定会攒钱攒到百万身家
and your fucking tits, I'd be a fucking millionaire.
幸亏  好心的上帝保佑
Instead, the good lord blessed me
我做了有道德感的男人
with a big dick and moral flexibility.
所以...我只多问一次
So... I'm going to ask you one more time,
不给个满意的回答我就狠狠地抽你们
or I swear to god I'm going to bitch-slap you so hard,
直到把你们打残为止  明白吗
your brand-new tits are going to pop out of your ass. Understood?
-艾迪在那儿  -小套房
- Where's Eddie? - The cabana.
女孩们  祝你们今天愉快
You girls have a good day.
我们认识彼此很长时间了
We've known each other a long time.
你从来不喜欢前戏
You've never been one for foreplay,
要不你省下那些扯淡的话  跟我直说吧
so why don't you just spare me the bullshit.
告诉我你要什么
Tell me what you need.
-有个活儿  -我知道
- There's a job. - I knew it.
-杰克  听我说完  -如果我没记错的话
- Just hear me out, Jack. - If I remember correctly,
凯伦  上次我帮你  差点进了班房
the last time I helped you out, Karen, I almost ended up on the wrong side of the grass.
没记错的话  你甚至不怎么想帮我
If I remember correctly, you weren't exactly putting up a fight.
凯伦  算了吧
Forget it, Karen.
杰克  我遇到麻烦了  真正的麻烦
I'm in trouble, Jack. Real trouble.
-不是真需要帮忙  我也不会在这儿  -别人
- I wouldn't be here unless I needed... - Someone.
...你  我需要你帮忙
...you. Unless I needed you.
杰克  我失去了整个团队
I lost my entire crew, Jack.
差点自己都没能活着出来
I barely got out alive.
事情搞砸了
And I lost the score.
艾迪要我赔偿所有损失  否则就杀了我
Eddie's going to kill me unless I pay him back.
这个活  大把的钱  小小的风险
This job? It's big money, small risk.
如果我们办成了
If we pull it off,
就有足够的钱付给艾迪  还...
it's enough money to pay back Eddie and...
...剩余不少
...and then some.
什么活儿
What's the job?
我喜欢国际象棋  完美的隐喻生活
I like chess. It's a perfect metaphor for life.
每颗棋子都有固定的位置和走法  就像我们
Every piece is bound to its nature, just like people.
-西蒙  你怎么看  -我不下棋
- What do you think, Simon? - I don't play.
你该学学的  鲍勃  你会吗
You really should. What about you, Bob?
-我更喜欢玩扑克  -我喜欢扑克
- I'm more of a poker guy. - Yeah, I like poker.
也是个好游戏  都是关于把你想要的
Also a great game. All about trying to make the most of what you got--
当然  股东先生  你找我来这儿干什么
yeah, sure, Mr. f. Listen, could you tell me what I'm doing here?
耐心点儿  只耽搁你一点时间
Bear with me. This will just take a second.
我有个问题要问你  请把手放在圣经上
I want you to put your hand on this Bible. I have something to ask you
保证你所说的话句句属实
and I want you to be perfectly honest with me.
-能知道原因... -请迁就一下
- Don't know why... - Indulge me.
我非常欣赏扑克
I appreciate poker.
它象征着希望  一种充满梦幻
It's a game of hope. A game of dreams.
和谎言的游戏  但是国际象棋  象征着秩序
A game of lies. But chess, it's a game of order.
这个卒子只能向一个方向移动
This pawn can only move one way.
向前移动  只能从斜对方吃掉对手的棋子
Move forward, can only take diagonally.
卒子努力工作  也许有一天能更进一步
And if it works really hard, it can become something better,
改变地位  就像你
something more. Like you.
鲍勃  你就是个卒子
You're a pawn, rob.
卒子不能做的事包括不能泄密给敌人的王后
And what pawns do not do is tell secrets to the enemy queen
-希望对方给陪他上床  -
- in hopes that she'll fuck him. -
股东先生  我从没说过半句
Mr. f, I never said a word!
你要干什么  别  老天  我靠
What are you doing?! No! No! God! Fuck! God!
手掌里的神经多着呢
So many nerves in the hand.
老天  操  我什么都没说
God! Fuck! God! I said nothing!
鲍勃  我们现在不是在玩扑克
We're not playing poker now, Robert.
而是在玩国际象棋
We're playing chess.
我是国王  西蒙是我的骑士
I am the king, Simon is my knight.
别管它
Leave it.
如果你够小心  愿意做出牺牲
You are a pawn, and if you aren't careful,
你才能成为一个小卒子  明白吗
you are going to be sacrificed. Do you understand that?
-明白  明白  -现在  罗伯特
- Yeah. Yeah. - Now, Robert,
关于我近期的商业冒险
what exactly did you tell Karen
你具体告诉了凯伦那些
regarding my latest business ventures?
-我跟她讲了联邦东部的活儿  -哦
- I told her about the eastern federal job. - Yes.
-还有开曼群岛的活儿  -哦
- I told her about the Cayman Islands job. - Yes.
还告诉了她关于装甲车的事情
I told her about the armored car.
-装甲运输车  -是  是的  先生
- The armored car. - Yeah. Yes, sir.
-那就是说  -就是说她什么事都知道
- That means... - That means she knows everything.
罗伯特这事我们怎么处理好呢
What are we going to do with Robert?
你会杀了我
You're going to kill me.
终究会的  对
Eventually, yeah.
终究会的
Eventually.
-装甲运输车  -是啊  差不多那样
- Armored car? - Yeah. More or less.
-这运动很蠢  -值得一试
- It's a stupid sport. - It was a nice shot.
-别犯傻了  -给
- Don't be a dick. - Here.
你怎么想
So what do you think?
杰里・斯普林格
我想你绝对会在杰里・斯普林格的脱口秀中亮相的
I think you've definitely secured yourself a spot on the Jerry springer show.
-我是说这个活儿  -杰克  我懂你的意思
- I mean about the job. - I know what you mean, Jack.
跟她合作绝对没什么好事
Nothing, and I mean nothing good,
没什么好结果的  兄弟
can come from working with her, man.
-那孩子怎么办  -你确定是你的种么
- What about the baby? - Are you sure it's even yours?
兄弟  她离开这么久  天知道跟谁搞在一起
She's been gone, man, shacking up with only god knows what.
-喂  喂  -对不起
- Hey, hey. - Sorry.
我只是希望她变了性子
I just keep hoping she's changed.
她上单活儿搞砸之后
And after the last job that she had that went bad
怀着孩子来找我  只是...
and now the baby, I just...
觉得也许她最终会有所改变  想要...
Maybe she'll finally want something different, something... something else.
-直说吧  -我
- Just say it. - Me.
也许她最终想要我
Yeah. Maybe she'll finally want me.
格雷丝  过来这里  狗狗
Grace! Come here, girl.
过来  来这里
Come on. Come here.
变个贵宾犬的样子看下
Be a poodle, Grace.
格雷丝  来  变成傻不拉叽的贵宾犬
Come on, be a little dumb-ass yippie poodle.
-来啊  -你在干吗
- Come on. - What're you doing?
-证明我的观点  -哦
- Proving a point. - Yeah?
-什么观点  -我不可能把
- Which is? - That I have a better chance
格雷丝变成一只傻傻的贵宾犬
of Grace turning into some dumb-ass poodle
你也不可能把一个冷血又控制欲极强的小婊子
than you do of getting this cold-hearted, manipulative bitch
变成安分守己的居家主妇
to settle down and live a normal life.
你以为未出世的孩子会改变她的本性吗
Oh, you think this kid is going to change who she is?
你以为那孩子会让她变得爱你吗
You think this kid is going to make her love you?
醒醒吧  朋友
Wake the fuck up, my friend.
她永远是那个凯伦  怀上孩子改变不了她
She's always going to be Karen. Now she's just Karen with a kid.
嗯
Yeah.
知道我为什么留着那张照片吗
You know why I keep that picture?
有一阵子我们总谈论要搬到圣.约翰岛去
There was a time when we used to talk about moving to St. John,
或其它类似的热带岛屿  开间潜水店
or some other tropical island, opening up a dive shop,
在世外桃源度过余生
living the rest of our lives in paradise.
就像海明威的小说里写的那样
Some real Hemingway-type shit.
那照片提醒着我为什么要...
And that picture was a reminder of why I do--
为什么我们要不停地争论这些
why we keep doing what we're doing.
你总是说什么风险啊
You're just taking these risks,
不义之财来之不易啊  但...
and making easy money the hard way, but...
我不能永远这样干下去
I can't keep doing this shit forever.
只要有机会
So if there's even the slightest chance
那怕一丝把这个白日梦变成真实的机会
that I can make
我也会想办法抓住
that stupid fucking pipe dream a reality, I'm going for it.
罗根  你不欠我什么
You don't owe me anything, Logan.
别这么说
Don't say that.
别TMD这么说
Don't you fucking say that.
我们是朋友  不是吗  关系就像一家人
We're friends, right? Practically fucking family?
-是啊  -那就没什么欠不欠的
- Yeah. - Then it's not about owing me.
跟欠人情一点关系都没有
It was never about that.
家人  朋友之间不谈这个
It's what friends do, it's what family does.
家人...朋友之间就得互相支持
We... we back each other's plays,
那怕从一开始就知道他们错得离谱
even when we absolutely know they're fucked from the get go.
-对吧  -我猜是这么回事
- Right? - Yeah, I guess so.
不要说"我猜这么着"  事实就是这样
Mm... no. No "i guess so." That's the way it is.
-那么  -那么
- So? - So?
让我们放手去做吧
Let's do this.
你为什么这般暴躁
Why are you so grumpy?
-就是那辆卡车吗  -
- Is that the truck? -
对  运送着价值3千万的宝石
That's the truck. 30 million in gems.
那是路线
That's the route.
-两天吗  -就两天
- Two days? - Two days.
-我们还得找个枪手  -必须的
- We're going to need a second gunman. - Definitely.
-还需要个好司机  -我知道上那儿找
- We're going to need a driver. - I know where to find one.
-技术非常好的司机  -我知道上那儿找
- A damn good driver. - I know where to find one.
德鲁
Drew.
安德鲁
Andrew.
安德鲁・赫茨伯格
Andrew Herzberg!
杰克  真的是你  真不敢相信我的眼睛
Jack? Jack! Really? I can't believe what I'm seeing!
-兄弟  好久不见  -就这家伙吗
- It's been a long time, brother. - - This guy?
这家伙能把卡车开到160英里时速吗
This guy flew in the 160th?
一脚上去  直到欧蓝德吉普前脸散架为止
Right up until breaking his commander's jaw.
嘘...夜间跟踪者不...
Sh... night stalkers don't--
有必要狂吐一番
that was completely necessary.
我百分百精神了
I feel a hundred percent.
-什么风把你吹到泰国来了  -
- What brings you to Thailand? -
我们在密西西比
We're in Mississippi.
真的吗
Really?
怎么可能
No fucking way.
能拿片纸巾之类的东西给我吗
Can we get a napkin or something?
-就那儿  -赫茨伯格
- Right there. - - Herzberg!
原来你在这儿  你这堆狗屎
There you are. You piece of shit!
-你又尿床了  -什么
- You pissed the bed again! - What?
你尿床了
Yeah. You pissed the bed!
亲爱的  我知道自己是成年人
Honey, I know I'm really big,
但是  你懂的  这太伤人了
but, you know, it still hurts.
你闻闻  你闻闻  闻闻你的尿骚味
Smell it. Smell it! Smell your filthy piss!
-好  是我  没错  -哦  是嘛
- All right. Well, it is me. Definitely. - Oh, yeah.
闻起来像威士忌  像失败者
Mm! It smells like whiskey, and failure,
像不可救药者  所有世界上最坏的东西
and sadness, and everything else bad in the world!
-这家伙一团糟  -
- This guy's a mess. -
比我上次见到他时强多了
He's doing much better than the last time I saw him.
别再问
Don't ask.
那么  你意下如何  德鲁
So, what are you thinking, drew?
你说的事情三岁小孩都做得来
I think this baby is capable of what you're asking for.
相信我  兄弟  只需稍稍改装几处地方
I'll just need to make a few modifications, but you know me, man.
-我就能把它开得飞起来  -
- I can drive, fly, or fuck-- -
你以为  还是你真懂
you think, or you know?
-抱歉  -这区别可大着呢
- Excuse me? - Yeah, there's a big difference.
你也许觉得自己是个了不起的司机
You may think you're one hell of a driver,
但我看到的只是个醉熏熏的酒鬼
but I know you're a drunk asshole.
她都不认识我
How could she possibly already know
-就敢断定我是个混蛋  -有什么问题
- that I'm an asshole? - What's the problem?
我们计划的成功与否
Our plan lies strictly
跟这个醉鬼司机的驾驶技术密切相关
on whether or not this drunk asshole can drive.
-你难道不担心吗  -
- That doesn't concern you? -
仍然没根没据地认定我是个混蛋
Again with the unsubstantiated asshole claim.
不  这我一点也不担心
No. It doesn't concern me.
-我见识过他的开车技术  -
- Because I've seen him drive. -
我也见识过他能醉成什么样子
And I've seen him drunk.
我从不醉酒开车  也许会喝得微醺
I never drive drunk. Buzzed, maybe.
宿醉状态开车  那肯定有过
Hung-over, absolutely.
但醉酒开车  从未有过
But drunk, never.
哦  那我算松了口气
Oh, that's a relief,
虽然这家伙还是满呕吐物的味道
coming from the guy whose breath still smells like puke.
我去车里等
I'll be in the car.
-她人不错  -天气不错哈
- She's nice. - This is a good day.
每次看到你这副硬汉模样
You've any idea
你知道在我眼里有多性感吗
how sexy you are when you do your tough guy routine?
-都布置好了吗  -当然  杰克  都布置妥当了
- Everything set? - Yes, Jack. Everything's set.
我喜欢你事事周到
I love how you worry about every single detail
在意每一个细节的样子
right up until the last minute.
- Karen... - Mm-hm?
-凯伦... -嗯哼
别
Stop.
我不能
I can't.
-是因为怯懦小姐吗  -她才不怯懦
- Because of Ms. milquetoast? - She's not milquetoast.
得了  杰克
Come on, Jack.
这女的就像香草  很普通无聊的
That girl is madame vanilla. Boring.
不是普通不普通的问题
It's not about madame vanilla.
真的跟简娜没关系  只跟...
It's not about Jenna, it's about...
-是我们的问题  是因为你  -嗯哼
- It's about us, it's you. - Mm-hm.
我要的  你要的  这一切完全不一样
And what I want, what you want and how that is... Completely different.
我不认为你我的需求有多不同
I don't think that what we want is that much different.
还缺个枪手
You don't have a second gunman.
你知道我有多能干
You know that I'm more than capable.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
-是我的活儿  -不行
- It's my job. - No.
我应该在卡车上
I should be on that truck.
如果你参与其中  我就撒手不干
If you're on this job, I walk, I'm gone.
那谁去
Then who?
安德鲁有个朋友
Andrew has a guy.
-哦  你相信他么  -我相信
- Oh, and you trust him? - Yeah. I trust Andrew.
好
Fine!
价值三千万的钻石在那辆卡车里吗
Thirty million in gems on this truck?
对  价值三千万的钻石
That's right, 30 million in gems.
-在黑市能卖个二千万吧  -也许不止
- We'll get 20 on the market. - Maybe more.
就算二千万
Let's just count on 20.
你欠艾迪八百万
You owe Eddie eight.
还剩一千二面万我们五个人分
That leaves roughly 12 for the five of us.
说得没错
That's correct.
然后呢
And then what?
唔  去圣.约翰岛买个房子
Well, then a house in St. John.
那个枪手  他叫什么名字
Who is it? Our second gunman?
尼古拉斯・西弗
Nicholas sepher.
安德鲁参军的时候就认识他了
Andrew knows him from his time in the army.
叫你别那么干  女人  别干
Don't you fucking do it, woman. Don't you do it!
谁让你给你前妻发短信呢
Maybe you should have not texted your ex-wife.
她母亲死了  别那么干
Her mother died! Do not fucking do it!
-你会下地狱的  -
- You can die in hell. -
一天到晚忍受你这唠叨婆
Oh, hell would be fucking paradise
我还是去地狱好了  那里才是伊甸园
compared to being married to you!
安德鲁跟我说过那个活儿
Andrew told me about the job.
我还没说完呢
We're not done with our talk.
兄弟  算上我
I'm in, man.
你要去  好啊  真伤透我的心哪
Yeah, you're in, all right, for a whole new world of hurt.
-你还没听细节呢  -不需要也不关心
- You haven't heard the details. - I don't need to. I don't care,
赫茨伯格去就行了
as long as it involves herzberg, it's going to get me
至少能让我远离这个家一段时间
the fuck outta this house for a while.
我们这个家那里惹你了
And what the hell's so wrong with our house?
-这活危险吗  -当然
- This thing fairly dangerous? - Sure.
-杰克  对吧  -对
- It's Jack, right? - Yeah.
杰克  我想念过去的生活
Well, Jack, I miss my life.
我还想找个硬汉子呢  总得有人做出牺牲
I miss getting fucked by a real man. We all make sacrifices.
你能闭嘴吗  不然掐死你
I will choke a bitch. Can you shut the fuck up?!
等着吃枪子吧
I hope you get shot.
杰克  看着我的眼睛  你看我快乐吗
Look in my eyes, Jack. Do I look happy to you?
-等着被人一枪打爆你的丁丁
- I hope you get dick shot. -
你看看  每天都这样
It's this. Every day.
一枪爆掉你
The worst kind of shot.
-杰克  你结婚了吗  有孩子  -咦
- You married, Jack? You got kids? - Ish.
-啊  兄弟  那感觉糟透了  -尼古拉斯
- Yeah. Well, it sucks, man. - Nicholas.
周围的每个人都开开心心的  除了我自己
Because everybody's happy except me. Me?
-尼古拉斯  -兄弟  我正想找个理由
- Nicholas! - Oh, man, I'm just looking for a reason
重新操上武器打爆某人的脑袋
to put a gun back in my hand, and a bullet in someone else's brain
在这之前  请告诉我
before I put one in my own. So tell me,
我们要对付的家伙  他们够坏吗
are the guys we're going up against, are they bad?
-不要脸的大公司  -太妙了
- Faceless corporation. - That's even better.
-尼古拉斯  -什么事
- Nicholas! - What?!
-我有阴虱  会传给你的  -
- I'm going to give you crabs. -
够了  把你的东西打包
That's it. Pack your shit.
带上那些猫狗  从我的房子里滚出去
Take those fucking rat dogs and get out of my house!
有一条狗可是你的哦  狗杂种
One of those dogs is yours, cocksucker.
我看起来像拉布拉多狗吗
Do I look like I wanted a fucking labradoodle?!
它可是我们的宝贝
She's our baby.
我要在你的笔记本上撒尿
I'm going to piss on your laptop.
她真会干的  抱歉
She will. Excuse me.
他做得来
He'll do.
前面的守卫  后面的守卫
Guard in the front. Guard in the back.
不是系统当天指定的司机
Anyone who tries to drive this thing
试图驾驶这卡车的话
other than the driver assigned for that day,
生物识别系统会自动让发动机熄火
biometric system automatically kills the engine.
卡车将再也不能启动  明白吗
Can't be restarted. Okay?
我们有20分钟左右的时间
We got 20 minutes or less.
最新科技的保险厢体
State-of-the-art vault.
一旦锁上  只能从内部打开
Once it's locked, only gets open from the inside.
想暴力切开它  得花上一个小时
It takes us about an hour, an hour to cut through.
-凯伦  我说得怎么样... -唔...
- How am I doing so far, Karen? - Mm...
尼克  我们做个预演
Let's run through this. Nick.
我阻止卡车
I stop the truck.
-我做掉守卫  -玻璃可是防弹的
- I take out the guard. - The glass is bulletproof.
呵  我用的可不是子弹
Well, it's a good thing I ain't using bullets.
-你用的是什么  -火花塞
- What're you using? - Spark plugs.
这些宝贝打爆防弹玻璃
These babies will break bulletproof glass
像我老婆捏爆我的蛋蛋一样简单
like my wife breaks my balls.
-罗根  -给队伍提供掩护
- Logan. - Provide overwatch.
-安德鲁  -我九点来接你们
- Andrew. - So at 0900 I pick you up,
驾驶一辆拖车
I drive the tow truck.
-你忘记装甲车了
- You forgot the armored car. -
对  下次一定记得
Right. I'll get it next time.
-混蛋  -还有凯伦
- Asshole. - And Karen.
哦  我就呆在家  又肥又胖的孕妇嘛
Oh, I stay here. Because I'm fat and pregnant.
-要明白  我只  -她的确是个胖孕妇
- You know, I was... - She's fat and pregnant.
就喜欢你这个样子
Just the way I like them.
我还没搞懂
I still don't know
你们计划怎么弄开卡车的保险车厢
how you plan on breaking into the truck's vault.
那可是个惊喜哦
Because it's a surprise.
-哦  -我喜欢惊喜
- Oh. - I love surprises.
大家都喜欢惊喜  对吧  伙计们
Mm-hm. We all like surprises, right, guys?
-罗根  -我不喜欢你  也不相信你
- Logan? - Yeah. Look, I don't like you, I don't fucking trust you.
你明天在说好的位置等
You be where you're supposed to be tomorrow.
车加满油  随时可以走
Car fueled up, ready to go.
-我会在那里的  -很好  如果你不听话
- I'll be there. - That's good to hear. Because if you're not,
我会找到你  等着你的孩子出生
I'll find you, wait for that fucking kid to be born,
受洗囡包  再给你个哥伦比亚式的死亡
and give you a Colombian necktie as a belated baby shower present.
好生动形象  你的意思已转达  没别的事吧
Graphic, but it gets your point across. Are we done?
不  话还没说完
No, we're not fucking done.
他现在跟简娜的关系好着呢
He's got a great thing going with Jenna.
你别给他添乱
He doesn't need you fucking it up.
难道你不认为
You don't think that he should be
他应该跟更好的人在一起嘛
with someone like that any more than he does.
换个说法  如果你给他添乱
Let me rephrase. You fuck this up,
利用了杰克的话  我会杀了你
you fuck over Jack, and I'll kill you.
你废话真是太多了
Now you're just being redundant.
套上去  好朋友  就像过去那样
Get on there, my little friend. Yeah. Like old times.
注意了  朋友们  好戏开场啦
Look alive, people. Showtime.
-尼克  准备好  -行动吧
- You ready, Nick? - Let's rock and roll.
怎么回事
What's going on?
靠
Fuck!
嘿  老兄  麻烦低下头
Hey, buddy! You might want to duck!
-我去下一个地点  -收到
- I'm going to the next location. - Copy that.
杰克  有麻烦了
Jack, we got a problem.
-多久  -老板  看六点钟方向
- How soon? - Check your six, boss.
快  开动  退一点  停住  就那儿
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon. Let's go. Come back. Back. Hold! Right there.
做好准备
Get ready.
德鲁  好了  目标到手
All right, drew. We gotta bounce.
快走
Let's go!
走
Let's go.
杰克  有三辆车子朝你的方向驶去
Jack, you got three vehicles headed your way.
-7个...
- And seven...
只剩6个坏家伙了
Six bad guys.
Welcome to the suck美国大兵的口头语
-三辆车跟着我们  -
- We got three on us. -
欢迎来到枪弹纷飞的世界
Welcome to the suck.
左  左转
Left! Go left!
-右边有辆车跟上来了  -看到了
- We got one on the right. - I got him.
靠  为什么坏家伙总是有自动武器
Shit! Why do the bad guys always have automatic weapons?
不好说  我正进入状态呢
I don't know, but I'm getting hard!
-你搞定他了  -搞定一个  剩两个
- You got him? - One down. Two to go.
杰克  看我的
There you go, Jackie boy!
见鬼
Shit!
打中了吗  杰克
You got him, Jackie boy!
靠近点
Get me closer.
-再近点  -人呢  怎么看不到
- Closer! - Where are they? I can't see them.
好  向前开
All right. Drive.
糟  看不到人
Shit, I don't see them!
走  走  左边  左边
Go! Go! On the left! On the left!
哇
Whoa!
那儿  就那儿
There. Right there!
天啦
Oh, god!
靠
Ah! Fuck!
糟不  刹车
Oh, shit! Brake!
-哇噢  -哇
- Oh! Yeah! - Whoo!
干得好
That a boy!
杰克  在这儿挤满警察之前
Jackie boy! We got about 15 minutes
-我们有15分钟  -两分钟就够了
- before this place is swarming with cops. - I just need two.
要不要给你电弧热喷枪
You want me to get you a thermal Lance?
不需要进到里面去
I don't need to get in.
把他赶出来就行了
I just need this guy to want out.
别搞了
Stop it!
手放背后  肚子朝下  肚子朝下趴地上
Hands behind your back! On your stomach! On your stomach!
手放背后  趴下
Hands behind your back! Down!
我了个去  好棒
Holy dingle berries!
-这值一大笔钱啊  -凯伦说的没错
- That's a lot of coin. - Just like Karen said.
凯伦说的没错
Yeah. Just like Karen said.
好了  快离开这里
All right. Let's get out of here.
-杰克  快撤  -好
- Come on, Jack. Let's rock and roll. - Yeah.
老板大人  我们去那儿
Where you going, boss man?
我有点事要查查  应该没啥
I just want to check something out. It's probably nothing.
你们先走吧  我...我会赶上来的
Just keep going, I'll... I'll catch up with you.
你可太心灵手巧了  真是奇迹
You were always a miracle worker with your hands.
换作我五分钟内肯定解不开
It would have taken me at least five minutes. Hey!
请不要乱动
Just stop right there.
-艾迪  现在怎么说  -怎么说吗
- So, what happens now, Eddie? - What happens now?
把那个小小的黑盒子乖乖地双手奉上
You're going to give me that little black box,
这就是我的说法
that's what happens now.
-然后呢  -然后嘛  可以放你一条生路
- Then what? - And then what? Then you get to live.
-艾迪  -什么
- Eddie! - What?
放她走
Let her go.
大英雄  把枪放下
Put the gun down, hero.
把枪放地上  踢过来给我
Put the gun down and kick it over here towards me.
-杰克  别那么干  -
- Don't do it, Jack. -
没人问你的意见  闭上你的嘴
Nobody asked you your opinion, so shut the fuck up!
大英雄  别担心
Don't worry, hero.
对你来说  她也许甜美体贴
With you, she might have liked it all sweet and gentle,
但对我而言  她更喜欢被粗暴对待
but with me, she liked it a little bit rougher.
对不对  亲爱的
Mm. Isn't that right, sweetheart?
把枪踢过来
Kick it over here to me!
你给他承诺了什么  承诺了什么
What did you promise him. Huh? What did you promised him?
钱  性  还是别的
Money? Sex? What?
不对
No.
他不知情  对不
He doesn't know? No.
你个贱人
You bitch.
我给你看样东西  看样东西
Let me show you something. Let me show you something.
-艾迪  -这就是你关心的吗
- Eddie. Eddie... - This? Is that what you're talking about?
艾迪  求你了  别
Eddie, please, no.
艾迪  艾迪
Eddie. Eddie!
跟肚子里的小宝贝说再见吧
Say bye-bye to the baby.
艾迪  别开枪
Don't do it, Eddie.
不要
No!
哦  不  怎么没小孩
Oh, no! No baby!
哦  不  居然没人受伤
Oh, no. No one's hurt.
开罗群岛那个活儿
So you did make it out
你还是做成了嘛  滚过去吧
of the Caymans with something. Get over there.
我猜她只是利用你搞到我手中的这个玩意
Guess she needed you to screw me out of this.
杰克  我已就位  但无法准确射击
Jack, I'm in position, but I can't get a clean shot.
-三... -真可惜
- Three... - - Shame really.
假如情况不同
If things were different,
你我合作能赚大钱
we could have made a lot of dough, you and me.
-二... -杰克  真是太可惜了
- Two... - Well, it's a real shame, Jack.
一  听你号令
One. On your go.
有时候事情就是办不成
Sometimes things just don't work out.
趴下
Down now!
-杰克  -快走
- Jack! - Let's go!
快撤
Let's roll!
-对  撤吧  -罗根  该撤了
- Yeah, let's go! - Logan, let's go.
-啊  -罗根  快来
- Ah! - Come on, Logan. Let's go.
她失血过多  应该送她去真正的医院
She's lost a lot of blood. You guys should take her to a real hospital.
这不行
We can't.
简娜  感激不尽
Jenna, I can't thank you enough.
你务必星期一之前离开这儿
Just be out of here by Monday.
杰克  别再给我电话
And Jack, don't ever call me again.
杰克会对凯伦发多大的火呀
I wouldn't want to be Karen right about now.
女人嘛
Women.
值得吗
Was it worth it?
嗯
Hm?
我在问你呢  值得吗
I asked you a question. Was it worth it?
-杰克  今天的一切都不在我的计划之内
- None of this was my plan, Jack. -
那你的计划是什么  凯伦
What was the plan, Karen?
-把我杀掉吗  -
- Was I supposed to get killed? -
不  按计划你会得到三千万
No. You were supposed to get 30 million.
那假怀孕是怎么回事
What about the fake pregnancy?
-我得确定  -确定什么  什么
- I had to make sure. - For what? For what?!
为了这玩意  这玩意吗
For this? Hm? This?
这个小玩意  它作什么用的
This little thing? What is this?
-钥匙  -解锁什么
- A key. - To what?
上帝帮我  凯伦
God help me, Karen!
你现在可没有肚子里的婴儿作倚仗
You don't have the baby inside to protect you.
一个保险柜
A safe.
另一个活儿吗
This is for another job?
保险柜里的货价值多少
And how much is in this safe?
唔  肯定不止三千万
Hm? It has to be a lot more than 30 million.
五千万  七千五百万吗
We're talking 50? 75?
-五亿  -我操  你就扯吧
- Half a billion. - Oh, fuck! Bullshit.
红钻
Red diamonds.
CIA黑色行动缴获的
CIA black op.
五百万一克拉  一百克拉价值五亿
Five million a carat, 100 carats, 500 million.
载着保险柜的飞机将于明天抵达
The plane with the safe flies in tomorrow,
加个油  然后飞走
just long enough to refuel, and then it's gone.
懂了  我懂了  那我们怎么下手
Oh, I see. I see. And what were you going to do?
走进去直接拿钻石吗
Just walk in there and take them?
计划中本来应该没人受伤的
No one was supposed to get hurt.
罗根受伤了
Logan did.
可以看出  你根本不在乎
Yeah, I see, not that you fucking care!
整个团队被盯上
I just earmarked my entire team.
进了死亡名单  艾迪会一直追杀我们
We have a death mark on us. Eddie's going to hunt us down.
-都是拜你所赐  -我真不是有意的
- So thank you very much! - I never meant for this to happen!
你手包里的超声波图是怎么回事
What about that sonogram I found in your purse?
那是真的  但孩子没能留住
It was real. But I lost the baby.
是我的吗
Was it mine?
去偷钻石吧  好好生活
Go get your diamonds. Have a nice life.
带着那五亿  有多远滚多远
With half a billion, you can afford to stay the fuck out of mine.
罗根  我真不想说
Come on, Logan. I could really use
"我早告诉你会这样"之类的话
that "i told you so" look right about now.
-我觉得你应该吻她的前额  -你说什么
- I think you should kiss her on the forehead. - What?
我是说  你该亲她一下之类的
I don't know. I mean, I feel like you should kiss her or something, you know?
-伙计  你这是  -让她有被爱的感觉
- Dude, have you-- - make her feel like she's loved.
她不信那套骗人的玩意
She's not into that sappy shit.
真的吗  老天  她都昏迷不醒了
Really? Jesus, she's sleeping.
还能拿你怎样
I mean, what is she going to do?
打爆你的脸  这就是她想干的
She'll break your fucking face. That's what she'll do.
嘿  欢迎回到人间  感觉如何
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Welcome back. How you feeling?
像在鬼门关走了一遭
Like I went dancing with a claymore.
噢  宝贝  宝贝
Oh, baby! Oh, baby!
-你怎么上这儿来了  宝贝  -
- What are you doing here, babe? -
真对不起  是...
I'm sorry. Is it...?
没事  宝贝  只是伤到了腿
No, no, baby. It's just my leg. Mm! It's just my leg.
感谢上帝  我上次不该说那些话的
Thank god! I didn't mean what I said.
我知道  我知道你是爱我的丁丁
I know. I know you love my dick.
-对不起  我... -这是你带来的吗
- I'm sorry. It's... - What did you bring me?
噢  杰克  我在门口发现了这东西
Oh. Jack, this was on the front doorstep for you.
-是什么来着  -某种遥控器和一个手机
- What is it? - Some kind of remote and a cell phone.
杰克
Jack.
你怎么走得这么急  好想念你这个好朋友
My new best friend jerk off. You left in such a hurry.
艾迪  什么事
What can I do for you, Eddie?
看来凯伦也不是那么冷血嘛
Turns out Karen isn't the cold-hearted bitch
她今天来了我的酒店
we made her out to be. She stopped by my hotel
带着你手里正拿着的那玩意  赔礼道歉
with what you now hold in your hands. Tried to make amends.
试图说服我这一切都是她的错
Tried to tell me that it was all her fault,
求我不要找你和你那帮反社会分子的麻烦
to leave you and your merry band of misfit hoods out of this.
-给你电话  亲爱的  打个招呼吧  -
- Here. Say hi, sweetheart. -
杰克  快逃
Just run, Jack.
说得对  杰克  快逃  有多快跑多快
That's right, Jack. Run. Run as fast as you can.
也许我不会让我手下追你
I probably won't use my considerable resources to find you
-并灭了你  -这种威胁我听得多了
- and put you down. - It's not the first time I've been threatened.
没人威胁你  只是想跟你谈个交易
Nobody's threatening you yet. I'm offering you a trade.
你以为我在乎啊  让她烂在地狱里吧
She can rot in hell, for all I care.
你这话我不得不承认  可能属实
That's probably an undeniable fact.
但这取决于你  是让她明天就开始腐烂发臭
But it's up to you whether she starts her stint tomorrow,
还是50年之后  杰克  你说呢
or 50 years from now. Come on, Jack.
我在给你实实在在的机会哦  看你怎么打动我了
I'm giving you a real opportunity here. Impress me.
大伙儿能给我俩几分钟吗
Can you guys give us a minute?
我能看出你为什么喜欢他
I can see why you like him.
艾迪  他不会帮你做这事的
He's not going to do the job, Eddie.
等着瞧
We'll see.
上帝啊  互相信任就这么难吗
Jesus. That must have been hard.
不懂你的意思
I don't follow.
靠  要她相信别人这么难
It must have been hard for her. Fuck.
我本不想说的  她把这一切搞砸了
I hate to be the one saying this. She fucked up.
很彻底
Big time.
但她至少敢挺身而出
But she at least tried to do the stand-up thing
向艾迪独揽罪过
and come clean to Eddie.
她还是想收拾烂摊子的
She tried to wipe our slates clean.
做这些需要勇气  她可以选择不做的
That took guts. She didn't have to do that.
不对  她自己闯下的祸  得由她自己解决
No. She got herself into this mess. She can get herself out.
-做件混账事  -什么
- Be a douche-bag. - What?
-做件混账事  -你说啥
杰克  你还是成不了那种人
Jack, you're not a douche-bag.
从你救我的那天起  我就意识到这一点
I knew that the moment you saved my life.
你不肯放弃我
You could have let me down.
你也不会放弃凯伦  有没有孩子都一样
You can't let Karen down, baby or no baby.
不  不  不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
这次不行  明白嘛
Not this time. Okay?
你睡在床上休息  等事情过去
You're going to sit this one out.
什么活儿
What's the job?
钻石  价值五亿
Half a bil, in diamonds.
为什么就不能只是抢个本地的珠宝店呢
Why can't it ever just be a local jewelry store?
那是摩根机场  俗称"落脚点"
That's Morgan airfield, the proverbial stomping ground
这机场是给所有机密任务  黑色行动用的
for all things clandestine and black ops.
飞机将于17小时内抵达  降落并加满油
Our plane lands in 17 hours. Touches down for a refuel only,
我们有15分钟的时间
giving us a window of 15 whole minutes.
我们需要做的是  在这段时间内
And all we gotta do in that time is walk in,
闯进飞机  打开保险柜
board the plane, crack the safe,
获取目标  然后大伙儿一起把东西带出来
download the score, and get the flock out of there.
你说得很具体  看起来很有把握
You say it like that, it almost sounds doable.
就说我们到了机场附近
Say we even get onto this airfield here,
知道机场地面有多少守卫要对付吗
do we know how many guards we're going to be dealing with on the ground?
不知道  只能走一步看一步
No. We'll have to figure that out in real time.
我是说  是50个还是100个守卫
I mean, but are we talking like 50 guards, or are we talking like 100 guards?
首先
First things first.
我们得想办法在不中弹的情况下靠近机场
We gotta get onto that airfield without getting shot.
我在做事呢  你说怎么办吧
I'm working. Okay? How are we going to do that?
-马尼拉  -马尼拉
- Manila? - Manila?
-那次好像没成功吧  -
- Didn't work out too good for you there. -
也许这次能大炫魅力呢
Maybe second time's the charm.
究竟谁是马尼拉
Who the hell is Manila?
-她真可爱啊  -呵
- She's adorable. - Yeah.
好了  德鲁  让他们忙乎吧  我去准备
All right, drew. Keep them busy while I get to work.
-你看那个小丑  -想吃点冰淇淋吗
- Check out this clown. - Want some ice cream?
搞什么飞机
What the fuck?
杰克  大门安全了  你可以行动了
The gate's clear, Jack. You're good to go.
阿普萨拉  记住  按尼克说的做
Apsara, remember, just like Nick showed you.
瞄准卡车  开枪就行
Aim for the truck and just pull the trigger.
别开枪  别开枪
Hold your fire. Hold your fire!
谁想舔一舔  过来啊  冰淇淋大甩卖
Anyone want a lick? Come get your ice cream! Come!
你穿着什么呢  这帮狗娘养的最好跑快点
What are you wearing? Fuckers better run.
快  快  快
Move, move, move!
好了  要给力啊  宝贝
All right, come on, baby.
见鬼
Shit!
-杰克  杰克  -再说一遍
- Jack! Jack! - Say again?
你得离开  快
You gotta go. Move!
我还在想你会不会出现呢
I was wondering if you were going to show up.
那里出差错了  艾迪认为我做不来吗
What's wrong? Eddie doesn't think I can do the job?
不如说是他不敢确定
Let's just say he wasn't sure
凯伦在你心目中是否比五个亿更占份量
Karen was worth the half a billion.
别把垃圾当宝贝
One man's trash and all.
你害我等了好久
What's taking so long?
你行  你上啊
You think you can go faster, be my guest.
-有主意吗  -有
- Got any ideas? - Yeah.
一个
One.
啊
Ahh!
-你欠我一次休假  -好说
- You owe me a vacation! - Fine.
二次休假
Two vacations.
杰克  你太让我失望了
Jack. You are a disappointment to me.
凯伦还有脸说你是最棒的
Karen said you were the best.
引用她的原话"米开朗基罗般的窃贼"
"The Michelangelo of thieves," to be exact.
我想最近可能有点生疏了
I may be getting a little rusty.
没事  反正你也活不了多久
It's all right. Soon you'll be dead.
先让我一枪爆了凯伦的脸再说
Right after I shoot Karen in the face.
说得好精彩  但你还是先耐心等等吧
Well, that's graphic. But you might want to just wait on that.
你的耐心可能值五亿美元哦
Could be worth half a billion dollars.
要我提醒嘛  钻石可在我手上
In case you missed it, I have the diamonds.
只要飞机一着陆
If the situation were reversed,
你就插不上手了
even I couldn't get them back once they land.
那是因为你不是米开朗基罗
That's because you're not Michelangelo.
艾迪  知道嘛  这些随机密钥生成器
You see, Eddie, the problem with those keygens,
很高明的玩意  要破解它
as remarkable as they are, they take forever.
15分钟的加油时间远远不够
Way more than the 15 minutes I had for refueling,
但你知道怎样做更快吗
but you know what goes real fast?
塞姆汀炸药
Semtex.
牛仔  你的话我在听
Okay, cowboy. You have my attention.
-带上钻石到...
- Bring the diamonds to-- -
-别讨价还价  我会通知你地址
negative. I'll call you with a location.
看来你忘了我手里有你的女人
You seem to forget that I have the girl.
你也忘了  在我眼里她就是个婊子
And you seem to forget she can be a real bitch.
值不了五个亿
It might not be worth a half a billion dollars to me.
杰克  好吧  按你说的来
Okay, Jack. Have it your way.
这女人真值得你在乎嘛
Your boy's got some sand.
-你怎么还没死  -心死而已
- You're not dead yet? - Only on the inside.
-杰克  对不起  -好感人的重聚
- I'm sorry, Jack. - Cozy little reunion.
打开它
Open it up.
我可做不到  密钥生成器丢了
Yeah, I can't. Keygen's gone. I lost it in the fall,
你这般神通广大的人  肯定会想到办法的
but a man with your resources, I'm sure you can figure a way into it
把它搬回你那受隐私保护的家  或是总部
in the privacy of your own home, or lair,
or whatever assholes like you have.
找个混蛋帮你打开吧
杰克  还有个小问题  我得杀了你
Oh, Jack. There's still the little matter of me killing you.
我们有约在先
We had a deal.
我从不跟偷我东西的贼做交易
I don't make deals with people that steal from me.
对生意影响太坏了
It's not good for business.
-我有狙击手  -狙击手完蛋了
- My sniper. - Your sniper's fucked.
什么都听不到吧
Can't hear anything.
我干扰了这里的所有通讯信号
I'm jamming all signals transmitting out of here.
想走出这个地方  门都没有
And I hope you don't think for one second I'm going to step out from under this thing.
不对
Nope.
趴下
Get down!
带他出去  快走
Get him out of here! Go! Come on!
他们朝楼顶方向跑了
They're headed for the roof.
凯伦  跟上
Karen, move!
警局  需要我帮你转接吗
911, how can I direct your call?
刚听到一声爆炸  声音非常大  我觉得
We just heard a bomb, really big, and I think...
老天  一大帮人带着枪冲进了酒店
Oh, my god! There's a whole bunch of men with guns in my hotel.
女士  警车正赶向案发地点  请安心等待
Okay, ma'am. We have vehicles responding right now. Just sit tight.
警局  需要我帮你转接吗
911, how can I direct your call?
好  警车正赶往案发地点
Yeah, we have vehicles responding to you right now.
上  上  上  上  上  上
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
上  上  上
Go! Go! Go!
-去楼顶  -杰克  真不要我帮忙吗
- Get to the roof. - You sure don't need me, Jack?
-当然  我一个人就行  -
- I'm sure I don't need you. -
杰克  你需要我
You need me, Jack.
糟糕
Ah! Shit!
杰克  没子弹了吗
Out of ammo, Jack? Huh?
紧张么
Getting nervous?
操你妈的
Fuck you!
-杰克  过来啊  狗杂种
- Get over there, Jack! Fucker!
我搞得定
I had him!
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
你个...
Son of a...
-多谢帮忙  -杰克  你又欠我一次休假
- Thanks for the help. - You owe me three vacations, Jack.
看来你的休假已经开始了
Looks like you're starting now.
兄弟  快点  要走啦  快
Move! Let's go, man! Come on!
站住
Stop!
站住  这一切
Stop! All of this,
就是为了爬上楼顶被乱枪扫死
just to get shot up here on this roof.
这就是你的计划吗
That's your plan?
去你的
Ish.
-嘣  -吃老娘一枪  混蛋
- Bang! - Eat a dick, asshole.
走吧
Come on!
飞机会带你去迈阿密  之后你想去那都行
This will take you to Miami and then... wherever you need to go.
杰克  你总能事事想周到
You always take care of everything, Jack.
你的分成
Your cut.
有点轻哦
Seems a little light.
如果你愿意的话  可以跟罗根谈谈
You can take it up with Logan if you'd like.
不了
No, I'll manage.
-凯伦  再见  -杰克...
- Goodbye, Karen. - Jack...
-承认吧  -承认什么
- Admit it. - Admit what?
你思念我  你思念这种感觉
You missed me. You missed this.
长久以来只有这种感觉才让你重新鲜活起来
This is the most alive you've felt in a long time.
-承认吧  -承认什么
- Admit it. - Admit what?
你自投罗网就是为了利用我们偷钻石和杀艾迪
You turned yourself in so we would have to steal the diamonds and kill Eddie.
我说过的  杰克  你总是事事想得周到
Like I said, you always take care of everything, Jack.
凯伦  再见
Goodbye, Karen.
再见  杰克
Bye, Jack.
喔  吼  吼  吼
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
真不敢相信你就这样白白给她奉上五百万美金
I can't believe you just handed her five million dollars.
-是她该得的  -才不是
- She earned it. - Like hell she did.
就当是你射伤她的补偿吧
Consider it a severance package for you shooting her.
-那是个意外
- That was an accident.
-"基本射击要领  枪目线过于模糊"
- "Marksmanship 101, boss. Gun target line was shit."
你知道人们怎么形容站街女吗
You know what they say about hookers.
杰克  我不知道人们怎么说的  解释一下
No, Jack. I don't know what they say about hookers. Enlighten me.
你付钱不是为了做爱
You don't pay them for sex.
而是为了让她们离开  这叫花钱买平安
You pay them to leave.
老板  很合理  就是为了晚上睡个安稳觉嘛
Justify it however you need to in order to sleep at night, boss.
-也可以说我是软心肠  -我说你是个蠢蛋
- Call me a softy. - I'll call you an idiot.
罗根  把今天这番话当做绝妙友谊的开端吧
Logan, I think this is the beginning of a beautiful friendship.
真的吗  我觉得更像是某件事的结局
Really? I see it more as an ending.
-罗根好吗  -她很好  谢谢
- How's Logan? - She's good. Thanks.
-这小狗是谁的  -我的
- And whose puppy is this? - It's mine.
对了  我...有书面证明
Uh, yeah, I... have proof.
我料到你会问起的  它叫罗伊
I figured you'd ask. His name is Roy.
-杰克  我... -
- Jack, I... -
简娜  听我说  请再给我一次机会
Look, Jenna, I was hoping for a second chance.
-我明白也许不值得你... -
- I know I don't deserve one-- - deserve?
值得  你是说值得吗
You want to talk about deserve?
杰克  我是不喜欢凯伦  但那也不应当成为
Jack, I know I don't look like Karen, but that doesn't mean I deserve
你那样对待我的理由
to be treated the way you treated me.
骗了我好几个星期  我都差点因你而死
You lied to me for weeks. You almost got me killed.
-我... -让我把话说完
- I... - Just let me finish.
是的  我非常喜欢你
Okay, I liked you, a lot.
你嘴甜  体贴  风趣  聪明  有绅士风度
You were sweet, caring, gentle, funny, smart.
在我眼里你还是拥有这些品质的
And then you were still all of those things,
但同时也是爱惹事生非的大坏蛋
but also this incredible bad-ass.
这点其实非常性感
Which was actually really sexy.
假如你想再次约我出去
But if you want to ask me out again, you're going to have to do more
买一条小狗  送些鲜花是远远不够的
than just buy a puppy and show up with flowers.
简娜  我...我不是...
Jenna, I... I don't--
好  要不以这个做为开始吧
okay, how about this for starters.
带上你的小狗
You come to my office in a few weeks,
过星期来办公室找我
with your new puppy, and if bad men haven't shown up
如果那时没有带着枪的坏人
with guns to kill the poor little innocent puppy
找上门来杀掉可怜无辜的小狗
by then,
也许你有机会约我共进晚餐
then maybe we have a chance at having a dinner date
枪林弹雨  摩托艇追逐是绝对不允许的
without bullets and boat chases.
-成交么  -成交
- Deal? - Deal.
然后
And then, after an indefinite number of dinner dates,
假设没有大肚子的前女友找上门来
assuming that no pregnant ex-girlfriends show up,
没有人再追杀我们
and no one shoots at us,
我也没找到你撒谎的蛛丝马迹
and if I don't catch you in any more lies,
在共度无数个晚餐约会的夜晚之后
you can somehow manage all of that,
可能  仅仅是可能
then maybe, just maybe,
我会给你个开着灯做爱的理由
I'll give you a reason to fuck with the lights on.
就说她会喜欢你的
Told you she'd like you. Yeah.
哦  杰克  "要不一起共进晚餐"总比
Well, "how about we go to dinner" is better than,
"去你妈的  我要叫警察了"  强多了
"go fuck yourself, Jack, I'm calling the cops."
-喂  -我不确定你会接电话
- Hello? - I didn't know if you'd pick up.
真不知道是你打来的
I didn't know it was you.
是我自做自受
I deserve that.
凯伦  你要说什么
What do you want, Karen?
我在圣.约翰岛买了幢房子
I bought that house on St. John.
很美  靠近水边
It's beautiful. It's on the water,
就像我们说过的那样
just like we talked about.
我甚至打算买一间潜水店
I'm even looking into buying a dive shop.
我为你感到开心  真的  但我不...
I'm happy for you, I really am, but I don't see...
见鬼  杰克  我真的不擅长道歉
Goddamn it! I'm no good at apologizing, Jack.
我从没就任何事给任何人道过歉
I've never apologized to anyone for anything.
我的意思是  我应该道歉的  只是...
Well, I mean, I was supposed to, I just...
只是说不出口
I just didn't.
杰克  事情过去之后  我变了很多
Jack, something changed me all through all this, you know,
看到我给你带来的伤害  我...
seeing the pain that I caused you, I...
我想跟你在一起
I want to be with you.
这房子  这些钱  没了你就...
This house, the money, without you it's...
...就真心无聊啊
...it's boring.
杰克  你知道怎么样才不无聊嘛
But you know what's not boring,
怎样才能永远不无聊吗  你我呆在一起
you know what's never boring, Jack? Us.
-你太孤独了  凯伦  找  -我爱你
- You're lonely, Karen. Find-- - I love you.
杰克  我爱你  这份感情直到永远
Jack, I love you. I think I've always loved you.
我知道你也是爱我的  我们可以再复合
And I know you love me. We could make this work.
我们会幸福的
We could be happy.
会幸福的
We can be happy.
杰克
Jack.
Jack?
杰克
-打错电话了  -说得准没错
- Wrong number. - Damn straight.